202 E Cypress St., Apt# 19 Glendale, CA 91205

Phone: 818-859-0391

Email: masis.garabedian@icloud.com

LinkedIn handle: masis-garabedian-124261122

Masis Garabedian

Highly qualified and analytical professional, with more than 6 years' experience in network administration, and implementation. Take pride in ability to effectively combine corporate objectives and values with personal and professional goals and work ethics.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Computer Physicians Inc. – Glendale, CA System Network Administrator October 2012 – Present

- Provide first point of contact for all Information Systems queries and requests.
- Implement and manage hardware and software solutions to small-medium business clients.
- Manage a file server. Shares and folder permissions
- Create users accounts, emails, security groups, distribution groups in Active Directory and Exchange
- Troubleshoot application, network, system issues for clients
- General Help Desk Activities (Desktop Support, VOIP Phone Support)
- Deploy, maintain iOS and Android devices for clients.
- Implement and maintain MAC OS workstations
- Updated existing workstations
- · Configured Symantec Antivirus servers for maintaining current virus definitions on workstations and servers
- Maintain Sonicwall firewalls for clients
- Plan, configure, and migrate to Microsoft Exchange environments to Office365
- Work in team to complete variety of projects
- Closely work with clients to analyze system requirements, needs and plan project and implement them.
- Deploy Logmein tool to manage clients workstations remotely
- Created and maintained backup strategies based on the client using: Barracuda, Intronis, Symantec
- Deploy network infrastructures using different switches: HP, Cisco, Ubquiti switches
- Analyze information to determine, recommend, and plan layout for type of computers, servers and peripheral equipment modifications.
- Responsible for creating and updating IT-related documentation (Policy manuals, Procedures manuals, Training manuals, Hardware/Software changes)
- Performed extensive product research and produced recommendations on new hardware

Freelance Graphic & Web Designer–Los Angeles, CA October 2011 – February 2015 Graphic and Web Designer

- Collaborate with clients to create vision, designs, and consistently meet deadlines and requirements
- Web design and development, Branding, Logo design, Illustrations & posters.
- Manage and coordinate graphic design projects from concept through completion.
- Design project presentation layouts, 3D Google Sketchup models, and Booklet covers.
- Coloring CAD drawings

Gulf House Engineering – Manama, Bahrain September 2009 – October 2011 Network Administrator

- Provide first point of contact for all Information Systems queries and requests.
- Manage a file server. Shares and folder permissions
- Create users accounts, emails, security groups, distribution groups in Active Directory and Exchange
- Troubleshoot application, network, system issues for clients
- General Help Desk Activities (Desktop Support, VOIP Phone Support)
- Performed extensive product research and produced recommendations on new hardware
- Updated existing workstations
- Developed a proper Active Directory Network

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating System/Software: Windows 10, MacOS, iOS, Android, Microsoft Exchange 2007/2010, Microsoft Server Family (2003, 2008, 2012) Advanced knowledge of Microsoft Office Suite (Excel, Word, Access, and PowerPoint). Programming R, Python, HTML & CSS, JavaScript, C#, C++, MySQL, PHP UX Sketch, InVision, Adobe xD, Tableau, Adobe Photoshop CS6, Adobe Illustrator CS6, Adobe Flash CS4, Adobe Dreamweaver CS4, Adobe Muse, Google Sketch Up, AutoCAD 2007, Revit 2015, Adobe Acrobat 9

CERTIFICATION

User Experience Research – University of Michigan (2019) Data Science – University of California Los Angeles (2018) User Experience – General Assembly (2017) Symantec Endpoint Sales Expert – Symantec (2012)

EDUCATION

University of Technology - Iraq

Bachelors of Science (BS) – Computer Engineering and Information Technology '09